Yanyan (Dora) Deng

New York, NY | 516-652-8341 | mogudyy@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/yanyan-dora-d-8177761a2/

SUMMARY

I excel in solving problems for stakeholders through efficient data reports that deliver reliable insights. I have contributed to increasing forecast accuracy in business planning by 65%. Extensive experience in developing and enhancing business-owned systems and applications using SQL, Power BI, and Python.

EXPERIENCE

Siemens Healthineers (Fourtune 500)

Tarrytown, NY

Data Analyst – Supply Chain Management

Aug.2021 – Aug.2023

- Leveraged **SQL** and **SAP** skills to conduct in root causes analysis for sales, financial, and product data, driving informed decision-making for sales operation planning and supply chain improvement
- Completed visualization dashboards in PowerBI, translating business needs into user stories to streamline analysis process
- Led cloud data migration by constructing **ETL pipeline**, optimizing workflow and the efficiency of 34 data reports processing, resulting in improved efficiency and data utilization

NYU Langone Fenvo Lab

New York, NY

Data Science Research Assistant Intern

Oct.2020 - Feb.2021

- Implemented Correlation, Significant level in R studio and Pandas in Python to formatted distributor data and recognize 450 mutant genes in 30k raw dataset
- Created scientific basis for biologists, leading scientist to explore unique diseases by visualization tool in R studio

Deloitte - NCAA March Data Crunch Madness Competition Data Scientist

New York, NY Jan.2020 - May.2020

- Predicted winning team of each game in 2020 NCAA with accuracy over 75% and log loss of 0.439
- Trained 17-year historical NCAA dataset with more than **150 variables** before feature selecting, tested models using machine learning algorithms like ANN and earned Honorable Mention (top10%) from judging panel

Gabelli School of Business

New York, NY

Data Analysis Teaching Assistant

Dec.2019 - Dec.2020

- Collected, aggregated, and analyzed 11GBs of Instagram data on Google Cloud to measure popularity of Product Tags using Pandas
- Built automated visualization dashboards by extracting data from MySQL server to track 50 fashion trends

Cerebral Artery LLC

Jersey City,NJ

Financial Data Analyst (part-time)

Oct.2023 - Present

Utilized SQL to ensure data accuracy and provided recommendations for financial planning analysis

EDUCATION

FORDHAM UNIVERSITY, GABELLI SCHOOL OF BUSINESS, NY

Aug.2019 - Dec.2020

MS, Information Technology GPA: 3.9/4.0

HOFSTRA UNIVERSITY, FRANK. ZARB SCHOOL OF BUSINESS, NY

Aug.2017 - May.2019

MS, Finance GPA: 3.4/4.0

Xi'an SHIYOU UNIVERSITY, China

Aug.2012 - May.2016

BS, Engineering GPA: 3.7/4.0

Skills

- Proficient in SQL, SAP, R, Python, PwerBI, Tableau, Azure Cloud
- Analytical insights and problem-solving skills
- Advanced communication and presentation abilities
- Gabelli Leadership Certification, Google Analytics Certification

Language

- Fluent in English, Chinese
- Intermediate in Spanish